<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-08T21:49:56+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Mechanical Pencil I Use</title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/mechanical-pencils/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Mechanical Pencil I Use"/><published>2024-12-01T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-01T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/mechanical-pencils</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/mechanical-pencils/"><![CDATA[<p>You know that saying about cameras - the best one is the one you have with you? Well, I’ve found the same holds true for mechanical pencils. And after years of frustration with lead-leaking pencils staining my clothes and stabbing me through my pockets, I found my perfect everyday companion a while back and finally got arond to touting it: the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pentel-Mechanical-Pencil-Kerry-P1035-AD/dp/B0013NE3VA">Pentel Sharp Kerry</a></p> <p>Let me back up a bit. Like many of us, I’ve had a love-hate relationship with mechanical pencils. While Wirecutter <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-mechanical-pencils/">crowned</a> the Blick Premier as their top pick (and it’s indeed an excellent pencil), I found my perfect match in their “Also great” pick: the Pentel Sharp Kerry. It solves the one problem that matters most to me - it has a cap. Simple, right? But this isn’t just any cap. The designers at Pentel clearly spent some serious time thinking about how people actually use their pencils.</p> <p>Here’s what makes it special: you can click the lead even with the cap posted on the back. Sounds minor, but it’s a game-changer. They even spring-loaded the cap’s finial (that’s the fancy word for the end bit) so it doesn’t rattle around when capped or separated from the pencil. It’s one of those small details that makes the whole thing feel premium.</p> <p>But my favorite part? The dual-purpose design of the eraser and lead chamber. When you’re writing with the cap posted on the back, pop off the end finial and you’ve got easy access to the eraser. Not using the pencil? Cap it, and that same removable end reveals the lead chamber for refills. It’s clever engineering that actually makes sense in daily use.</p> <p>The Kerry isn’t trying to be the fanciest mechanical pencil out there. Instead, it focuses on being reliable and practical. The 0.5mm lead writes smoothly, and the whole thing feels solid without being heavy. Plus, when you’re actually writing, you can rotate the pencil to get the sharpest part of the lead on the paper without the pocket clip getting in your way.</p> <p>Is it perfect? Maybe not. But it’s the first mechanical pencil I’ve actually wanted to carry with me every day. And isn’t that what really matters? Because just like that camera in your phone, the best mechanical pencil is absolutely the one you’ll actually have with you when you need it.</p> <p>And for me, that’s the Kerry. No more lead-stained pockets. No more accidentally stabbing myself. Just a reliable writing tool that’s ready when I am. Sometimes the best solutions are the simplest ones - even if it took a ton of pencil evolution and testing on my part to get there.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I tried a lot of mechanical pencils; this is the one I use and why]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Estimating the Probability of Not Proposing an Ethereum Block</title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/eth-validator-block-probability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Estimating the Probability of Not Proposing an Ethereum Block"/><published>2024-01-27T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/eth-validator-block-probability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2024/eth-validator-block-probability/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Plot</strong>: <a href="https://www.yewjin.com/assets/html/eth_block_probability.html">yewjin.com/assets/html/eth_block_probability.html</a> is a plot of the probabilities where you can fit in your own values.</p> <p><strong>Note (June 2024)</strong>: This blog post is updated regularly (ideally daily!) with the current eligible ETH value from the blockchain.</p> <p>As an Ethereum staker, one of the key aspects of participation in the network is decentralization … OK … nevermind it’s the opportunity to propose a block and hope for winning the block lottery. The probability of getting this chance, however, depends on several factors, most notably the total number of validators in the network and the number of validators you control. Here’s how to calculate the probability of not proposing a block over different time periods - an hour, a day, a week, or even a month. Because, admit it, you are only asking this question after not getting a block proposal for that long and you are asking: “WHAT ARE THE ODDS?!”</p> <p>The Ethereum PoS protocol, specifically in the context of block validation, operates with discrete time units called slots. A new block is proposed in each slot by a randomly selected validator. The probability of a specific validator being chosen for any given slot is inversely proportional to the total number of effective ETH balance of each validator. See <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/consensus-mechanisms/pos/block-proposal/">Block Proposal (ethereum.org)</a></p> <ol> <li><strong>Total Eligible ETH (N):</strong> The total amount of eligible ETH in the network. As of 2024-12-08 12:42, it’s approximately 34315892 ETH.</li> <li><strong>Your ETH (V):</strong> The amount of ETH you have staked.</li> <li><strong>Time Period (T):</strong> The duration for which you want to calculate the probability, measured in slots. (Note: The Ethereum network typically operates with a slot time of 12 seconds.)</li> </ol> <h3 id="calculating-the-probability">Calculating the Probability</h3> <p>The probability of not proposing a block in a single slot, for a user with V ETH, is calculated as follows:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Probability (Single Slot) = 1 - (V / N)
</code></pre></div></div> <p>To extend this to a specific time period, T slots, the formula becomes:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Probability (T Slots) = (1 - (V / N))^T
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Handy number of slots in various time periods</p> <ul> <li><strong>For One Hour:</strong> With T = 300 slots (assuming 12 seconds per slot).</li> <li><strong>For One Day:</strong> T = 7,200 slots.</li> <li><strong>For One Week:</strong> T = 50,400 slots.</li> <li><strong>For One Month:</strong> Approximating a month as 30 days, T = 216,000 slots.</li> </ul> <h2 id="probabilities-for-32-eth">Probabilities for 32 ETH</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Probability of not proposing a block in one slot:</strong> \(1 - \frac{32}{34315892}\)</li> <li><strong>One Hour (300 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{32}{34315892} \right)^{300}\)</li> <li><strong>One Day (7,200 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{32}{34315892} \right)^{7200}\)</li> <li><strong>One Week (50,400 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{32}{34315892} \right)^{50400}\)</li> <li><strong>One Month (approx. 30 days, 216,000 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{32}{34315892} \right)^{216000}\)</li> </ul> <h3 id="summary">Summary</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one hour:</strong> Approximately 99.97%</li> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one day:</strong> Approximately 99.33%</li> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one week:</strong> Approximately 95.41%</li> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one month:</strong> Approximately 81.76%</li> </ul> <h2 id="probabilities-for-3200-eth">Probabilities for 3200 ETH</h2> <ul> <li><strong>Probability of not proposing a block in one slot:</strong> \(1 - \frac{3200}{34315892}\)</li> <li><strong>One Hour (300 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{3200}{34315892} \right)^{300}\)</li> <li><strong>One Day (7,200 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{3200}{34315892} \right)^{7200}\)</li> <li><strong>One Week (50,400 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{3200}{34315892} \right)^{50400}\)</li> <li><strong>One Month (approx. 30 days, 216,000 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{3200}{34315892} \right)^{216000}\)</li> </ul> <h3 id="summary-1">Summary</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one hour:</strong> Approximately 97.24%</li> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one day:</strong> Approximately 51.10%</li> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one week:</strong> Approximately 0.91%</li> <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one month:</strong> Practically 0% (very close to zero)</li> </ul> <h1 id="calculating-the-probability-of-proposing-at-least-b-blocks">Calculating the Probability of Proposing At Least B Blocks</h1> <p>To calculate the probability of proposing at least B blocks, we can use the Poisson distribution as an approximation for large T, where T is the total number of slots and p is the probability of proposing a block in a slot. The parameter lambda (λ) for the Poisson distribution is:</p> \[\lambda = T \times \left( \frac{V}{N} \right)\] <p>The cumulative probability of proposing at least B blocks is:</p> \[P(\text{proposing at least } B \text{ blocks}) = 1 - \sum\_{k=0}^{B-1} \frac{\lambda^k e^{-\lambda}}{k!}\] <p>where \(\lambda = T \times \left( \frac{V}{N} \right)\).</p> <h3 id="example-probabilities-for-32-eth">Example Probabilities for 32 ETH</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Probability of proposing at least 1 block in one day:</strong> \(1 - \sum*{k=0}^{0} \frac{\lambda*{1 \, day}^k e^{-\lambda\_{1 \, day}}}{k!}\)</li> <li><strong>Probability of proposing at least 2 blocks in one week:</strong> \(1 - \sum*{k=0}^{1} \frac{\lambda*{1 \, week}^k e^{-\lambda\_{1 \, week}}}{k!}\)</li> <li><strong>Probability of proposing at least 5 blocks in one month:</strong> \(1 - \sum*{k=0}^{4} \frac{\lambda*{1 \, month}^k e^{-\lambda\_{1 \, month}}}{k!}\)</li> </ul> <p>Finally, if you want to see the latest statistics on block proposal frequency, see <a href="https://luckystaker.com/home/">LuckyStaker.com</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When your solo staking setup isn't proposing, you are asking WHAT ARE THE ODDS?!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>