<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://yewjin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://yewjin.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-28T06:26:52+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yew Jin</title><subtitle>About Yew Jin. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Software 3.0 - Learn to Conduct, Not Just Code</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/developer-dance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software 3.0 - Learn to Conduct, Not Just Code"/><published>2025-06-26T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/developer-dance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/developer-dance/"><![CDATA[<p>Having watched Andrej Karpathy’s latest talk “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LCEmiRjPEtQ">Software Is Changing (Again)</a>” - it’s not just a technical update, it’s a fundamental shift in how we think about building software. His framework of Software 1.0 (hand-coded) → 2.0 (neural nets) → 3.0 (natural language) captures something profound - these aren’t successive replacements but complementary tools in our expanding toolkit. This is augmentation, not abdication of our intelligence.</p> <p>The reality check is sobering: ignore the hype and realize that while LLMs are powerful, they still need a tight leash. They hallucinate, mix facts randomly, and require careful guardrails. “Vibe coding” is magical for weekend prototypes and personal projects, but becomes risky in production environments. It’s prone to cascading bugs, security vulnerabilities, and mounting technical debt. As many are discovering, it’s both mentally exhausting and somewhat overhyped for serious development - often coding itself into a corner and require fundamental rewrites when productionizing.</p> <p>This is fine since what Karpathy (and others like myself) really advocate for is augmented intelligence - think Iron Man’s suit enhancing human capabilities, not replacing them. We’re moving toward human-in-the-loop systems with adjustable autonomy sliders, where AI amplifies our abilities rather than operating independently. The practical approach? Use AI to rapidly prototype and explore ideas, but stay deeply engaged to review, test, and iterate. Those ambiguous LLM outputs demand structured pipelines with human verification at critical junctures.</p> <p>So what should we do now?</p> <p>For early-career engineers: practice “supervised vibe coding” - generate small functions with AI but trace through every line to understand the logic. Mid-level engineers: use LLMs as architectural rubber ducks and for boilerplate reduction, but own the design decisions. Senior engineers: create AI-safe architectures where generated components can fail gracefully, and establish team guidelines for responsible AI usage. Everyone should maintain a “playground” environment for AI experiments, separate from production.</p> <p>And if you are a product builder, the question becomes: how do we make augmentation the centerpiece of your product? What does it mean to be not human-first, not AI-first, but human-AI-first?</p> <p>This crystallizes what remains irreplaceable: human judgment, ethics, creativity, and the ability to navigate ambiguity - precisely where AI struggles most. The future belongs to those who master human-AI orchestration, combining clear architectural vision with creative judgment. We need to be amplified by AI yet firmly anchored in human insight and understanding.</p> <p>Bottom line: AI won’t replace developers who understand their craft, but those who can do this dance between the technical and human will define the next era. The skill to develop isn’t just coding - it’s orchestrating AI capabilities while knowing when human wisdom is non-negotiable.</p> <p>Learn to conduct the symphony, not just play an instrument. Enjoy the wave.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ai"/><category term="sosftwareengineering"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections on Karpathy's AI manifesto and why the future belongs to human-AI orchestrators]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coping with Burnout</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-burnout-practices/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coping with Burnout"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:42+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:42+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-burnout-practices</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-burnout-practices/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_its-been-a-few-weeks-since-i-posted-and-activity-7329206012123455489-AyGn?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>It’s been a few weeks since I posted and I wanted to share strategies that help me cope with not burning out while still valuing the work - AI continues to be moving at a fast pace and there is so much for us to get plug in and be part of the future!</p> <ul> <li> <p>For me, a crucial first step has been identifying what delights versus what drains me. Tracking which tasks and interactions energize or deplete me has helped me recognize exactly where to set boundaries.</p> </li> <li> <p>I’ve started prioritizing work that genuinely excites me by asking: “What makes me lose track of time?” and “Which projects align with my values?” When we anchor our days in activities that spark enthusiasm, they become sustainable foundations rather than occasional bright spots.</p> </li> <li> <p>Building recovery rituals into my schedule has been essential. Those small breaks throughout the day aren’t luxuries—they’re necessities. Even 5 minutes to walk or breathe helps interrupt the stress cycle before it overwhelms.</p> </li> <li> <p>I practice emotional awareness through mindful observation. Rather than identifying with feelings (“I am stressed”), I notice them with curiosity (“There is stress present now”). Seeing emotions as experiences passing through awareness—not defining who I am—helps me respond from a centered place.</p> </li> <li> <p>Perhaps most importantly, I’m reconnecting with my professional identity not being me. Much of our suffering comes from attaching to any aspect of ourselves. When work becomes our primary source of meaning, challenges there can shake our entire foundation. By nurturing different facets of my life and remembering that no single role defines me, I’ve found a more balanced perspective that creates natural resilience to the inevitable ups and downs of work.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Take care of yourselves, friends.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical strategies for preventing burnout while staying engaged with fast-paced work, including identifying energy patterns and building recovery rituals.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Experiencing Burnout</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-experiencing-burnout/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Experiencing Burnout"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:41+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:41+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-experiencing-burnout</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-experiencing-burnout/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_i-wanted-to-share-something-personal-that-activity-7318439407835836416-JCpx?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>I wanted to share something personal that’s been affecting me lately—and that I know many others quietly experience too. I’ve been noticeably absent from posting recently, and I want to be transparent about why: I’ve been experiencing burnout.</p> <p>Thankfully, I caught it early. I’ve learned to recognize the signs and have been taking steps to address it.</p> <p>Burnout isn’t just exhaustion—it often has layers. For me, it showed up in three ways:</p> <ul> <li>Overload: Taking on too much work or responsibility and pushing beyond capacity</li> <li>Value misalignment: Working on tasks misaligned with my values or interests</li> <li>Lack of rest: Not getting proper, restorative rest</li> </ul> <p>Looking back, I realized I was experiencing early signs of all three at once. I felt overwhelmed by what I thought I had to carry, drained by things that didn’t energize me, and not allowing myself enough space to truly rest.</p> <p>I’ve experienced significant burnout before, and whether it’s mild or severe, it tends to creep in—until it suddenly hits and leaves me disconnected from myself, others, and work.</p> <p>It feels vulnerable sharing this, but I believe it’s important to normalize these conversations.</p> <p>Right now, I’ve been taking steps to reset—re-evaluating priorities, creating space for real rest, and focusing on the work that genuinely motivates me. If you’re feeling the same, know you’re not alone—and it’s okay to pause, reset, and realign.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A personal and vulnerable sharing about experiencing burnout, its three manifestations (overload, misalignment, lack of rest), and the importance of normalizing these conversations.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seeing Possibilities</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-seeing-possibilities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeing Possibilities"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:40+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:40+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-seeing-possibilities</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-seeing-possibilities/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_about-seeing-the-possibilities-others-dont-activity-7312840134800904194-xf3Z?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>About seeing the possibilities others don’t… I’ve noticed something interesting about how I approach problems differently from others. This became clearer to me during my PhD and has continued throughout my career as a software engineer. I am often the one who comes up with the “crazy ideas” that make people tilt their heads… mostly they don’t work but sometimes they do, and they’re always fun to explore! There is also a neat psychological trick of giving others the permission to say their “crazy ideas” once there are already other (dumb) crazy ideas out there.</p> <p>I’ve been reflecting on where these insights come from, and I’ve recognized distinct patterns:</p> <ul> <li>When I question the assumptions that everyone else takes for granted. Those moments when I ask “Why do we always do it this way?” or “Does this constraint actually exist?” have led to some of my best breakthroughs. Sometimes what seems like an immovable limitation is just a habit we’ve never challenged.</li> <li>When I make unexpected connections between ideas. Some of my strongest contributions came from bringing together concepts from different domains—like when I applied Web spelling correction to document spelling correction. Sure the style of writing is different, but the underlying tech feels like they should be transferrable, plus the Web spelling correction system is automagically updated with new words!</li> <li>When conventional approaches don’t work, it means we have to try new things. Innovative solutions have emerged when the standard playbook failed completely and we had no choice but to explore outside our comfort zone. These moments of being forced to abandon the familiar have often led to our most elegant solutions. I would say that doing a PhD really forces one in this space, after all, your goal is do something which no one else has done before!</li> <li>Be willing to try ideas, even though this is a balance as I can’t try everything, and so I had to build an intuition over time of how much to push here, but as they say, “In theory, theory and practice are the same. In practice, they are not.”</li> </ul> <p>Not all my ideas work out—plenty crash and burn spectacularly. But I’ve learned that being open to pursuing these insights, even when they seem risky, has made me a better software engineer and problem-solver.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How questioning assumptions, making unexpected connections, and trying unconventional approaches leads to breakthrough solutions that others might miss.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intuition</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-intuition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intuition"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:39+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:39+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-intuition</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-intuition/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_as-software-engineers-we-pride-ourselves-activity-7311595226978992129-2yVD?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>As software engineers, we pride ourselves on being data-driven and making totally rational decisions. But there’s an underrated tool in our toolkit: intuition.</p> <p>Apologies if I offend your sensibility here, but there is so much to us and the world, and there is a mysterious power to our subconscious mind. Our unconscious mind constantly processes information at a scale our conscious mind cannot match. It detects subtle patterns, synthesizes seemingly unrelated data points, and makes rapid assessments based on years of accumulated experience.</p> <p>That’s why I’ve learned to trust my gut on softer decisions:</p> <ul> <li>When something feels “off” about a product direction</li> <li>When a teammate’s stated concerns doesn’t align with intuitive concerns</li> <li>When a team restructuring looks good on paper but doesn’t feel right</li> </ul> <p>Our unconscious mind processes social cues, nonverbal signals, and complex patterns that analytics often miss. These “gut feelings” aren’t random - they’re our brain’s sophisticated pattern-recognition system at work.</p> <p>However, intuition of course has its limits. I would be cautious when relying on it in an unfamiliar domain (your unconscious needs data to work with), strong emotions are clouding judgment (fear, excitement, attachment), or using it in situations which require precise quantitative analysis.</p> <p>The best decisions often come from balancing analytical thinking with intuitive wisdom. My approach: listen to my gut, but verify with data when possible. Also work with teammates who aren’t afraid to tell you your decision is dumb. :-)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why software engineers should trust their intuition for softer decisions while understanding its limits, and how the unconscious mind processes complex patterns.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Strategic Focus</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-strategic-focus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strategic Focus"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:38+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:38+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-strategic-focus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-strategic-focus/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_as-an-engineering-director-i-used-to-think-activity-7310544134568562688-f7cV?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>As an engineering director, I used to think that a goal is to train myself to juggle multiple priorities simultaneously. Then I realized something: my multitasking wasn’t a strength—it was diluting my impact.</p> <p>Here’s how I’ve transformed my leadership approach with this in mind:</p> <ol> <li> <p>Choose ONE strategic priority daily (60-90 minutes): Whether it’s diving deep into decisions for a flagship product, crafting our strategic roadmap, or working on a technical problem. My day-to-day norm is to be pulled in countless directions—choosing a daily focus creates compound impact over time.</p> </li> <li> <p>Create focus-friendly zones:</p> </li> </ol> <ul> <li>Dedicated “focus time” blocked on my calendar</li> <li>Replaced recurring status meetings with asynchronous updates</li> <li>Collaborating with my team on my week’s focus to align calendars accordingly</li> </ul> <ol> <li>Build sustainable energy practices:</li> </ol> <ul> <li>Daily walks to clear mental space</li> <li>Unscheduled “tea time” to recharge as needed</li> </ul> <p>When I focus on a single strategic priority each day, I get things done and help unblock others. I find that it’s useful to do this but it takes a conscious effort and intention to take control of your time and focus.</p> <p>In this age of scattered attention, this might be our most important responsibility.</p> <p>What’s your strategic focus today?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How shifting from multitasking to daily strategic focus as an engineering director creates compound impact through dedicated time blocks and sustainable energy practices.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grounding myself</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-grounding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grounding myself"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:37+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:37+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-grounding</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-grounding/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_in-a-world-spinning-faster-by-the-day-the-activity-7308736524857090049-16iz?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>In a world spinning faster by the day, the only thing I truly control is myself.</p> <p>The tech landscape shifts beneath our feet—layoffs, AI disrupting entire industries, startup booms and busts seemingly overnight. It’s easy to feel powerless when your job security or career path suddenly looks uncertain.</p> <p>We waste precious energy trying to predict market changes or control organizational decisions beyond our influence. I’ve learned that detaching from these external forces doesn’t mean indifference—it’s about strategic investment of limited resources.</p> <p>When faced with industry turbulence, I focus on what I can influence: heads down and building, developing adaptable skills, nurturing my professional network, maintaining a financial safety net, and choosing my response to setbacks.</p> <p>This mindset shift transformed my relationship with change. Instead of anxiety about organizational hurdles or potential layoffs, I concentrate on continuing to land impact and be resilient enough to thrive if anything unfortunate should happen anyway.</p> <p>In professional settings, this means accepting volatile conditions while choosing my own response. In personal growth, it means becoming my own source of validation rather than seeking it from unstable external structures.</p> <p>The world will keep spinning at its own pace. The question is: how will you direct your energy in the face of changes you can’t control?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How focusing on what you can control rather than external forces like layoffs and industry changes creates resilience and strategic energy investment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slowing down to move fast</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-rest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slowing down to move fast"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:36+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:36+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-rest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-rest/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_slowing-down-to-move-fast-or-why-i-choose-activity-7306720390800711680-6h1l?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>Slowing down to move fast, or why I choose to rest. Last week during a 3-day training program, I made a choice that would have felt impossible to me years ago: I opted out of the elective modules to simply rest and reflect–to be fair, that was an option presented which make the choice obvious to me since it was clear that I needed it.</p> <p>In our achievement-oriented culture, there’s a persistent myth that our worth is tied to our productivity. This false belief suggests that if we’re not constantly doing, we’re somehow failing or being lazy.</p> <p>What I’m learning, particularly as I’ve gotten older, is that the urge to slow down isn’t laziness at all – it’s a biological signal worth listening to. There’s a clarity that comes with age and experience about when to push and when to pause. Perhaps this is part of where the saying “Youth is wasted on the young” is getting at.</p> <p>When we’re constantly giving our all to our jobs, side projects, and responsibilities, we leave no space for deep thinking, creativity, or even understanding who we truly are.</p> <p>I find that I can only sustain focused productivity for a few hours daily. Working beyond that point often leads to diminishing returns and, eventually, burnout. Yet somehow, society has normalized the expectation of constant productivity with terms like “996” which refers a work schedule in China where employees are expected to work from 9 a.m. to 9 p.m., six days a week, or 60+ hour work weeks.</p> <p>This reminds me of the concept of “lying flat” (“tang ping” in Mandarin) or “quiet quitting” which describes personal rejections of societal pressures to overwork and over-achieve.</p> <p>Perhaps it doesn’t need to be this way, that our work can sustainable, productive, even joyful.</p> <p>This weekend, I’m breaking my usual pattern. No side projects. No getting ahead for next week. Just rest. I’m sharing this because I suspect I’m not alone in struggling with the guilt that comes with choosing recovery.</p> <p>In my twenties, I might have pushed through, worn the exhaustion like a badge of honor. Now I recognize that was never sustainable or even effective. But what if creating space for ourselves isn’t self-indulgence but necessary maintenance? What if resting isn’t the opposite of productivity but a crucial component of sustainable achievement? Perhaps this is the wisdom that comes with experience – understanding that our energy is finite and worthy of protection.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why choosing rest over constant productivity isn't laziness but necessary maintenance, and how slowing down can lead to more sustainable achievement.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GenAI Defining Moment</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-genai-defining/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GenAI Defining Moment"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:35+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:35+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-genai-defining</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-genai-defining/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_ive-been-thinking-about-defining-moments-activity-7305723154549653504-q0SU?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>I’ve been thinking about defining moments lately - those experiences that shape who we are and what we become.</p> <p>As I watch the AI revolution unfold, I can’t help but be reminded of when I first joined Google in 2007, thinking that I missed the boat with the whole “make information universally accessible” dream. Some feel overwhelmed and left behind, worried their expertise will be rendered obsolete. Others see unprecedented opportunity.</p> <p>The truth? This is our defining moment. The other time I felt this compelled was the emergence of Deep Learning, but while that felt like a step up, it didn’t feel like a step change.</p> <p>We don’t need AGI for this transformation to fundamentally change how we work and create. The tools available today are already reshaping industries in ways that seemed impossible just months ago.</p> <p>Yes, there’s fear. Yes, there’s uncertainty. Voice actors seeing work dry up, analysts watching their roles automated, creative professionals questioning their future, software engineers no longer needed to code up projects.</p> <p>But remember: defining moments aren’t just about elevation and surprise. They’re about insight, pride, and connection. They’re about discovering something new about yourself and the world.</p> <p>We get to decide:</p> <ul> <li>Will we create the future or just wait for it?</li> <li>Will we ride this exponential wave or be swept away by it?</li> <li>Will we find meaning in the transformation or only see what’s being lost?</li> </ul> <p>The chaos and uncertainty we’re experiencing now is the birthplace of innovation.</p> <p>This moment isn’t just happening to us - we’re happening to it. We’re shaping it.</p> <p>Ten, maybe even just five or less, years from now, we’ll look back at this period with 20/20 clarity. The question is: will you remember it as the time you stepped up and helped define how these technologies serve humanity? Or as the moment that passed you by?</p> <p>Choose to make this your defining moment. The future is calling.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="ai"/><category term="insights"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why the AI revolution represents our defining moment - a choice between creating the future or waiting for it, with parallels to joining Google in 2007.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GenAI Secret Sauce</title><link href="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-genai-secret/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GenAI Secret Sauce"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:34+00:00</updated><id>https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-genai-secret</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yewjin.com/blog/2025/linkedin-genai-secret/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_ai-revolution-what-nobody-else-is-seeing-activity-7304302169141170177-VA3X?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>The real secret sauce in AI startups and products? Not code, but gold-standard evaluation data.</p> <p>Just listened to YC’s Lightcone podcast where YC folks gathered insights about the AI revolution.</p> <p>One founder revealed that might seem counterintuitive (around 8-minute mark): the most valuable asset his company built wasn’t their codebase—it was their evaluation dataset. The carefully labeled “gold standard” that defines what correct AI outputs should look like.</p> <p>This resonates deeply with me. In a world where models are becoming increasingly commoditized and accessible, competitive advantage isn’t just about which model you use, but how impactful your use case is and how you’re applying these models to solve that use case. The secret sauce to creating the best application is how well you can measure and improve its performance for your specific use case.</p> <p>“Anybody has access to the models, but nobody has the eval set.” That’s the moat many aren’t seeing.</p> <p>Building AI products is more about creating these proprietary datasets to guide your systems to deliver tangible value.</p> <p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0LMK5JYkB94</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="ai"/><category term="insights"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why evaluation datasets, not code, are the real competitive advantage in AI startups - insights from a YC founder about building proprietary "gold standard" data.]]></summary></entry></feed>