<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yew Jin</title><subtitle>About Yew Jin. </subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-communication-skills/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-communication-skills</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-communication-skills/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_two-core-communication-skills-every-engineering-activity-7270283734174593024--oX_?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>Two Core Communication Skills Every Engineering Leader Must Master One crucial skillset that distinguishes great engineering leaders is their ability to communicate effectively. While coding skills got us started in our careers, communication becomes increasingly critical as we progress from tech lead to manager to director. Here are two fundamental communications skills at various levels:</p> <p>Skill #1: Listening The first skill might surprise you – it’s not about speaking, but listening. And I don’t mean the kind of listening where you’re already formulating your response while the other person is talking.</p> <ul> <li> <p>As TL As a TL, listening is about understanding technical details and team dynamics. e.g., when I was TL and teammates shared concerns about our architecture, my instinct was to jump to solutions. But by practicing active listening, our discussions started to be perceived more as helping, and helped to address root causes rather than symptoms.</p> </li> <li> <p>As a Manager The scope expands to career aspirations, team dynamics, and unstated concerns. Regular 1:1s became opportunities to understand what truly motivated each team member, helping build stronger, more cohesive teams.</p> </li> <li> <p>As a Director Through skip-level meetings and cross-team interactions, you’re listening for patterns: Are teams aligned? Where are the collaboration bottlenecks? Catching misalignments early prevents much larger problems down the road.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Skill #2: Explaining The second critical skill is explaining with precision and adaptability. This isn’t about dumbing things down – it’s about meeting people where they are.</p> <ul> <li> <p>As TL Your challenge is translating complex technical concepts into actionable insights. Start with the why, then the what, then the how. This structure helps engineers understand not just implementation details, but the reasoning behind architectural decisions.</p> </li> <li> <p>As a Manager The focus shifts to explaining expectations, feedback, and organizational context. One technique that’s served me well: preview the message, present details, then review key takeaways.</p> </li> <li> <p>As a Director You’re often explaining strategy and vision to diverse audiences. The key is adapting your message without losing its essence. Concrete examples and clear success metrics help bridge the gap between high-level strategy and day-to-day execution.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Communicating effectively is a multiplier effect These skills compound powerfully. Strong listening leads to better understanding, which enables more effective explanation. Like any technical skill, communication improves with deliberate practice. Start small – maybe active listening in your next few 1:1s, or clearer explanations in team meetings. Each level brings new challenges, but mastering these core skills builds a solid foundation for leadership.</p> <p>What communication challenges are you facing in your current role?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-1/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_as-someone-who-has-worked-on-growth-in-search-activity-7175209200740937729-nYu-?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>As someone who has worked on growth in Search for the past 5 years, I have thought more than I care to admit about the key principles and strategies that can help unlock sustainable growth - here they are:</p> <h1 id="small-g-and-big-g-growth-is-not-growth">small g and big G: growth is not Growth</h1> <ul> <li>Pick which g/G refers to what, then stick with it.</li> <li>“growth” (small g) refers to the repeatable approach of optimizing the growth funnel: acquisition, churn resurrection, engagement, retention, and churn reduction.</li> <li>“Growth” (big G) acts on the core value proposition and requires product-market fit.</li> <li>It’s crucial for organizations to understand and prioritize both aspects, ensuring that “growth” efforts align with the overarching “Growth” strategy.</li> </ul> <h1 id="hope-is-not-a-good-growth-strategy">Hope is not a (good) growth strategy</h1> <ul> <li>Unfortunately just because it’s not a good strategy doesn’t stop people from using it</li> <li>Relying on hope alone is a common pitfall that many folks new to growth planning fall into, often leading to disappointment and wasted resources.</li> <li>Successful growth requires a data-driven approach, clear goals, and a well-defined strategy backed by actionable plans and metrics.</li> <li>While hope can provide motivation, it should not be the foundation of a growth strategy.</li> </ul> <h1 id="its-all-about-the-funnel-funnel-funnel">It’s all about the funnel funnel funnel</h1> <ul> <li>The growth funnel is a fundamental concept that governs the success of any product or service.</li> <li>It’s math - it governs the world - please deal with it. I am not trying to throw shade at your product.</li> <li>Small changes that impact a large audience at the top of the funnel can often yield better results than big changes targeting a smaller slice of traffic.</li> <li>Organizations must prioritize and focus on the most critical stages of the funnel to maximize their growth efforts.</li> </ul> <p>Do these resonate? Feel free to chat with me if you’re at Google for more (hard-fought) growth thoughts and examples on which these are based on.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-2/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_since-my-posting-on-growth-garnered-lots-activity-7175824858574913537-HOkn?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>Since my posting on growth garnered lots of positive feedback, here’s the second set of growth insights since I literally couldn’t fit all of them into one LinkedIn post… (As I said, I think too much about growth.)</p> <p>This set is focused on the operational aspects of making growth work in organizations:</p> <h1 id="growth-portfolio-management">Growth Portfolio management</h1> <ul> <li>Effective growth requires a balanced approach to resource allocation between “known” levers (which tend to be smaller but more reliable impact) versus “bets” (which tend to have higher growth potential)</li> <li>Examples of “known” levers could include optimizing existing acquisition channels, reducing churn, or optimizing an existing retention channel. “Bets” might include exploring new entry points, launching new products, or testing innovative growth strategies.</li> <li>Prioritize and fund proven growth levers before exploring unknown or experimental initiatives to ensure more predictable and reliable growth.</li> <li>Regularly review and adjust the growth portfolio based on performance and changing circumstances to stay ahead of the curve - invest in the ideas that work, drop ideas that don’t work quickly.</li> </ul> <h1 id="there-is-no-silver-bullet--you-grow-by-getting-many-things-right">There is no silver bullet – you grow by getting many things right</h1> <ul> <li>Sustained growth is the result of consistently executing well across multiple areas of the growth funnel.</li> <li>While there may be a few larger growth levers that can have a significant impact, focusing solely on these levers is not enough. Successful growth requires a holistic approach that addresses every stage of the funnel.</li> <li>Growth is a war of attrition, where you must systematically optimize and improve each piece of the growth funnel over time. This requires patience, persistence, and a willingness to experiment and iterate.</li> <li>Getting many things right requires a long-term perspective. Sustainable growth is not achieved overnight but through consistent effort and optimization over time.</li> </ul> <h1 id="logistics-wins-growth">Logistics wins growth</h1> <ul> <li>“Infantry wins battles, logistics wins wars.” - John J. Pershing, commander of the American Expeditionary Force in Europe during World War I</li> <li>“Logistics wins growth too.” - Yew Jin Lim</li> <li>In the context of growth, “logistics” refers to the data infrastructure, experimentation platforms, analytics, and even the organizational set up, including cross-functional collaborations.</li> <li>Growth is a team sport, and organizations need to break down silos and foster strong partnerships between teams such as product, engineering, data science, UX, and more.</li> <li>Does your organization track growth?</li> <li>Does it measure itself against growth?</li> <li>How does the team learn about progress towards growth? It’s not just the leads, it’s everyone on the team should be thinking and tracking towards what works, and what doesn’t.</li> <li>Are you involving cross-functional partners such as data science, program management, UX design, UX research, and others?</li> </ul> <p>Share your experiences and insights in the comments below!</p> <p>Remember, logistics wins growth!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-growth-3/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_guess-this-is-going-to-be-regular-series-activity-7177379520885239808-Ovax?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>Guess this is going to be regular series until I start repeating too much or I get sick of writing these down, but here’s the third installment of my growth insights and execution series.</p> <h1 id="the-effectiveness-of-a-growth-funnel-is-as-good-as-its-weakest-point">The effectiveness of a growth funnel is as good as its weakest point</h1> <ul> <li>A chain is only as strong as its weakest link, and a growth funnel is only as effective as its biggest bottleneck.</li> <li>Optimize the weakest stages of your growth funnel to unlock the full potential of your entire customer acquisition process.</li> <li>Continuously monitor and strengthen the weakest points in your growth funnel to maintain a well-oiled, high-performing machine.</li> </ul> <p>Remember, your growth funnel is a complex system with many interdependent parts. Identifying and addressing the weakest points can have a tremendous impact on your overall growth performance.</p> <h1 id="roofshots-small-steps-giant-leaps">Roofshots: Small Steps, Giant Leaps</h1> <ul> <li>Roofshots are achievable, short-term improvements that compound over time, leading to significant long-term growth and success. They prove that consistent, incremental improvements can lead to game-changing results.</li> <li>Ranking, triggering, and signal changes for search is an example of roofshots; so are datacenter innovations like improving electrical efficiencies, etc.</li> <li>Compound growth is the secret sauce: A 1.3X improvement per quarter adds up to a moonshot-level 23.3X improvement in under 3 years.</li> <li>Roofshots are the unsung heroes quietly driving sustainable growth and innovation behind the scenes.</li> <li>See Roofshot Manifesto by Luiz André Barroso https://fontoura.org/papers/barroso.pdf</li> </ul> <p>Don’t underestimate the power of small, consistent improvements. Roofshots may not grab headlines like moonshots, but they are the foundation of sustainable, long-term growth.</p> <h1 id="mediocre-ideas-executed-well-are-better-than-great-ideas-executed-poorly">Mediocre ideas executed well are better than great ideas executed poorly</h1> <ul> <li>Execution is king: A mediocre idea with excellent execution will outperform a brilliant idea with poor execution every time.</li> <li>Ideas are just the starting point; it’s the quality of execution that determines the success of growth initiatives.</li> <li>Pivot to practicality: Focus on ideas that can be implemented successfully, rather than chasing great ideas that prove difficult to execute effectively.</li> <li>Build a strong foundation: Executing well on a mediocre idea puts you in a better position to pivot to a great idea later, as you’ll have a solid base of users, resources, and market understanding.</li> </ul> <p>Remember, ideas are just the beginning. It’s the execution that truly matters. Prioritize ideas that can be implemented effectively, and use the strength of your execution to position yourself for even greater success in the future.</p> <p>I hope these insights resonate with you and provide some actionable tips for your own growth efforts. As always, feel free to share your own experiences and insights in the comments below. Let’s keep the growth conversation going!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-impact-mindset-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-impact-mindset-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-impact-mindset-2/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_ive-been-thinking-more-about-what-separates-activity-7285401281400131584-oH69?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>I’ve been thinking more about what separates the moments of real impact from everything else. Building from my last post - here are three key behaviors keep emerging from my experiences, both from my own and from observing teammates who do well - patterns that turned good work into meaningful change.</p> <p>First, it’s about constantly finding ways to be more valuable. The biggest breakthroughs happened when I looked beyond my job description and asked “what really matters here?” Sometimes the most important work wasn’t officially assigned to anyone. By focusing on what the organization truly needed, rather than just checking boxes, I found opportunities to make a lasting difference.</p> <p>Second, I learned that impact isn’t about titles – it’s about stepping up when needed. The times I’m most proud of and when I see others do well weren’t when they had formal authority, but when they tackled those persistent problems that everyone complained about but no one owned. Those ‘small’ issues that, left unaddressed, quietly drained team productivity day after day. Building trust with teammates, respecting their time and expertise, and sharing credit for wins – these were the real keys to leading effectively.</p> <p>Finally, there’s something powerful about being known as someone who finishes what they start. When challenges arise, it’s tempting to alert others and hope someone else handles them. But real impact comes from taking ownership and tackling problems head-on with resilience and determination. I’ve learned to prepare better by getting different perspectives early, being clear upfront about what support I need, and yes, sometimes knowing when to let go of something that’s not working.</p> <p>Looking back, these weren’t just random behaviors. They were deliberate choices about how to show up every day. The impact didn’t come from just working harder – it came from working differently, from seeing opportunities where others saw obstacles, and from staying committed even when things got tough.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-innovation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-innovation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-innovation/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_after-years-of-leading-innovation-projects-activity-7256034640019234816-Vb-G?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>After years of leading innovation projects in big tech, here are three critical lessons I’ve learned about navigating the complexity:</p> <ol> <li>Patience is required</li> </ol> <ul> <li>“Overnight successes” are typically month or years in the making</li> <li>The reality: Quick strategy → slow execution (and that’s okay)</li> <li>But more often it’s even: No clear strategy→ big goal, so we’ll need to figure it out along the way!</li> <li>Focus on progress over perfection - overthinking kills momentum</li> <li>Key is measuring progress differently: track small wins, not just final outcomes</li> <li>Keep moving forward incrementally, especially in complex environments</li> <li>Build a culture where consistent progress beats endless planning</li> </ul> <ol> <li>Keeping the team and leadership motivated</li> </ol> <ul> <li>The vision needs constant reinforcement - both up and down the org</li> <li>Use clear, memorable messaging to keep goals front-and-center</li> <li>Maintain a “brag doc” - it’s not bragging, it’s strategic communication</li> <li>Make progress visible and celebrate every milestone, no matter how small</li> <li>Connect each team member’s work to the larger mission</li> <li>Pro tip: Your internal “marketing” needs to resonate with both your team and leadership - speak both languages (I need to learn to do this better myself!)</li> </ul> <ol> <li>Navigate Organizational Debt</li> </ol> <ul> <li>Big tech = big organizational debt (it’s inevitable)</li> <li>Think of it like tech debt: it compounds from avoided decisions</li> <li>Watch for the signs: outdated processes, delayed restructuring, excessive caution</li> <li>Don’t waste energy fighting bureaucracy - it exists for a reason</li> <li>Instead, focus on maintaining momentum despite the constraints</li> <li>Empower your team to spot and solve inefficiencies</li> <li>Remember: Anyone at any level can drive progress with the right motivation</li> </ul> <p>Innovation in big tech isn’t just about breakthrough moments - it’s about consistent forward motion and helping your team navigate complexity while staying focused on what truly matters.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-moving-fast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-moving-fast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-moving-fast/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_i-wanted-to-share-three-principles-that-have-activity-7298114499113336833-2xe8?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>I wanted to share three principles that have consistently guided how I approach projects:</p> <ul> <li> <p>Embrace the power of iteration over revolution. I’ve learned that sustainable success rarely comes from “moonshots.” Instead, I focus on consistent, incremental improvements - “roofshots.” Each iteration builds on the last, creating a compound effect that’s both reliable and powerful. It’s about making measurable progress every single day, rather than waiting for that one breakthrough moment. Even with bold ideas, I push for quick demos to validate the approach before scaling. Learning fast beats guessing big.</p> </li> <li> <p>Impact before exploration. Every project serves one of two goals: delivering impact or opening doors for future innovation. But impact comes first. High-impact work earns the space and resources to explore new frontiers, ensuring we solve today’s problems while preparing for tomorrow’s.</p> </li> <li> <p>Plan thoroughly, execute adaptively. Strategy and roadmaps are critical, but reality rarely unfolds as planned. The key? Invest in planning, but stay flexible enough to pivot when new data demands it.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Isn’t it about “move fast and break things?” Maybe in some cases. But I’ve found that consistent, thoughtful progress—paired with strategic exploration and adaptive planning—has led to more sustainable and meaningful outcomes for my team and me.</p> <p>And the most important thing? Get started and keep going.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-navigating-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-navigating-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-navigating-change/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_change-is-hard-but-change-is-also-inevitable-activity-7299149598470651905-5jpt?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>Change is hard. But change is also inevitable - as the saying goes, the only constant in life is change.</p> <p>Recently, I experienced a significant change at work. While navigating this transition, I’ve been using these 5 strategies that are helping me stay grounded and move forward:</p> <ul> <li> <p>Acceptance: The more energy we spend fighting “what is,” the less we have for moving forward. I’ve learned that acceptance isn’t giving up—it’s giving yourself a solid place to start from.</p> </li> <li> <p>Grounding: I continue to ground myself through daily meditation each morning. Whether it’s quiet reflection, journaling, or gentle movement, these routines have become my daily anchor when everything else feels uncertain.</p> </li> <li> <p>Responding: I’ve taken time to reflect and develop specific strategies for responding to challenges. Sometimes the simplest tools such as pausing and taking deep breathes, a quick walk, talking to a friend all make the biggest difference in how we navigate change.</p> </li> <li> <p>Focusing on What I Can Control: In times of change, I focus on what’s within my reach. Even small actions matter. Each day, I identify one thing I can influence and start there. Progress compounds, even in small steps.</p> </li> <li> <p>Simplifying Daily Decisions: I’m saving my mental energy for big decisions by simplifying the small ones. Creating routines and planning in advance helps reduce daily choices. When life feels complex, making fewer decisions helps maintain clarity.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Remember: Change is inevitable, but growth is optional. How are you choosing to navigate life’s transitions?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-self-awareness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T18:07:34+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-self-awareness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/2025-06-18-linkedin-self-awareness/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_software-engineering-management-activity-7264714747848065024-1GTL?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>In a recent post, I explored building concentric circles of competency. Many of you were intrigued by the first step, ‘Know Thyself’.</p> <p>Having spent years in Big Tech, I’ve seen how essential self-awareness is to career growth. Let me break it down:</p> <p>A. Understanding Who You Are Now It’s about honest self-reflection: accepting your strengths and weaknesses. This goes beyond your resume. Genuine self-awareness creates the confidence needed to pursue goals aligned with your strengths.</p> <p>Examine the gap between how others perceive you and how you see yourself. Ask yourself:</p> <ul> <li>“What do my colleagues see as my strengths?”</li> <li>“Where do they think I could improve?”</li> </ul> <p>Solicit feedback. These moments of disconnection—or alignment—are golden opportunities. I remember being told as a TLM, “Stop trying to code, you’re blocking the team…” That’s when I knew I should focus on engineering management. On the other hand, folks often tell me they enjoy my creative approach to problems, and I enjoy riffing on ideas and building new things (ask me about my LLM-powered e-ink display of bad jokes!)</p> <p>Performance programs like GRAD at Google are valuable sources of information. Don’t shy away from introspection. This step is hard. It demands that you dig in and find yourself.</p> <p>B. Understanding Who You Want to Be Forget about a perfect 10-year plan. This is about active exploration. Clarity comes from action.</p> <p>Instead of waiting to become the leader I aspired to be, I started embodying those qualities early on. I was already contributing to architectural decisions, mentoring, and taking ownership. This “act as if” approach is about growing into your aspirations. Want to be seen as a leader? Volunteer to lead a project or mentor a new hire. Aspire to be a technical expert? Deep dive into a tech and share your knowledge. Do, don’t ask. (or at least make it asking for forgiveness)</p> <p>C. Understanding How to Get There The bridge between who you are and who you want to be is built through strategic action.</p> <p>Your path doesn’t have to be revolutionary – it needs to be authentic. Sometimes, the best opportunities exist within your current role. This might involve seeking a mentor, identifying projects that align with your goals, or investing in your development.</p> <p>Remember that growth isn’t always linear. Stay focused on your goals and remain adaptable.</p> <p>The Most Important Question</p> <p>“What energizes me most?” This emerged through years of paying attention to what activities left me feeling fulfilled. For a while, I did a ton of “what the business needed,” and it left me drained. This isn’t about a perfect plan; it’s about understanding your motivations.</p> <p>When you align your strengths with your aspirations and find opportunities that energize you, work becomes a path to continuous growth.</p> <p>Take some time to reflect. What energizes you? Where do you want to go?</p> <p>Now go do it.</p> <p>https://yewjin.com/blog/2022/software-engineering-managing/</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Coping with Burnout</title><link href="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/linkedin-burnout-practices/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coping with Burnout"/><published>2025-06-18T08:00:42+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-18T08:00:42+00:00</updated><id>https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/linkedin-burnout-practices</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://limyewjin.github.io/blog/2025/linkedin-burnout-practices/"><![CDATA[<p>Note to the reader: This is a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/yewjinlim_its-been-a-few-weeks-since-i-posted-and-activity-7329206012123455489-AyGn?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAD4xmMBhqAf0RkmEot2NJkJA3gvq31H7Os">repost</a> from LinkedIn</p> <p>It’s been a few weeks since I posted and I wanted to share strategies that help me cope with not burning out while still valuing the work - AI continues to be moving at a fast pace and there is so much for us to get plug in and be part of the future!</p> <ul> <li> <p>For me, a crucial first step has been identifying what delights versus what drains me. Tracking which tasks and interactions energize or deplete me has helped me recognize exactly where to set boundaries.</p> </li> <li> <p>I’ve started prioritizing work that genuinely excites me by asking: “What makes me lose track of time?” and “Which projects align with my values?” When we anchor our days in activities that spark enthusiasm, they become sustainable foundations rather than occasional bright spots.</p> </li> <li> <p>Building recovery rituals into my schedule has been essential. Those small breaks throughout the day aren’t luxuries—they’re necessities. Even 5 minutes to walk or breathe helps interrupt the stress cycle before it overwhelms.</p> </li> <li> <p>I practice emotional awareness through mindful observation. Rather than identifying with feelings (“I am stressed”), I notice them with curiosity (“There is stress present now”). Seeing emotions as experiences passing through awareness—not defining who I am—helps me respond from a centered place.</p> </li> <li> <p>Perhaps most importantly, I’m reconnecting with my professional identity not being me. Much of our suffering comes from attaching to any aspect of ourselves. When work becomes our primary source of meaning, challenges there can shake our entire foundation. By nurturing different facets of my life and remembering that no single role defines me, I’ve found a more balanced perspective that creates natural resilience to the inevitable ups and downs of work.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Take care of yourselves, friends.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="linkedin"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practical strategies for preventing burnout while staying engaged with fast-paced work, including identifying energy patterns and building recovery rituals.]]></summary></entry></feed>